welcome to episode number 302 of
dobrodošli u epizodu broj 302 od
category 5 technology TV i'm your host
kategorija 5 tehnologija TV Ja sam vaš domaćin
Ravi Ferguson and I am your co-host the
Ravi Ferguson i ja smo vaš domaćin
gang oh I'm Eric kid Eric how are you
gang oh Ja sam Eric kid Eric kako si
Robbie doing good man you I am well I'm
Robbie radi dobrog čoveka, ja sam dobro
looking forward to a fun show tonight
radujem se večernjoj zabavnoj predstavi
I'm happy to be here and I am just glad
Sretan sam što sam ovdje i samo mi je drago
to be alive when I tell you what's
da budem živ kada ti kažem šta je
coming up in news what do you think good
u vijestima šta misliš dobro
idea do it we can do that excellent okay
Ideja je da to uradimo odlično
coming up in the newsroom twisted light
pojavio se u redakciji iskrivljenog svjetla
can transmit data at 1.6 terabits per
može prenositi podatke na 1.6 terabita po
second through fiber optic cable
drugi kroz optički kabl
facebook gave a researcher $20,000 for
facebook je dao istraživaču $ 20,000 za
discovering a bug and reporting it back
otkrivanje bug-a i njegovo prijavljivanje
to them a pair of windows viruses or by
njima par prozora virusa ili
Ryan are helping each other survive
Ryan jedni drugima pomažu da prežive
Voyager 1 may soon leave our solar
Voyager 1 može uskoro napustiti našu solarnu energiju
system two men enter interstellar space
sistem dva čovjeka ulaze u međuzvezdani prostor
Wow the researchers have found a way to
Wow istraživači su pronašli način da to urade
cram 1000 terabytes onto a single DVD
strpati 1000 terabajta na jedan DVD
and half-life 2 is now stable on Linux
i polu-život 2 je sada stabilan na Linuxu
stick around these stories are coming up
držati se tih priča
later in the show awesome Eric do you
kasnije u emisiji strašan Erik ti
remember when we reviewed the world's
Sjetite se kada smo pregledali svijet
smallest computer I remember that the
Najmanji kompjuter sećam se toga
company rikomagic the manufacturers
kompanija rikomagic proizvođači
those uh that was episode number one I
to je bila epizoda broj jedan
don't know parmeet 283 go check it out
ne znam parmeet 283 idite da pogledate
if you haven't seen yet the world's
ako još niste videli svet
smallest computer rikomagic has
najmanji kompjuterski rikomagic ima
continued to develop their products and
i dalje razvijaju svoje proizvode i
tonight we're going to be showing you
večeras ćemo vam pokazati
some of the latest and greatest from
neke od najnovijih i najvećih iz
them also we've got a ton of viewer
njih takođe imamo tona gledalaca
questions tonight so we're going to
pitanja večeras, tako da ćemo
crack into the mailbag and we're going
pucajte u vrećicu i idemo
to have another viewer question
da ima drugo pitanje gledaoca
extravaganza this time we're opening up
ekstravaganca ovog puta otvaramo
the phone lines so feel free to pick up
telefonske linije se slobodno javljaju
the phone give us a call to 545 cat5 TV
telefon nas poziva na 545 cat5 TV
to get your question and 4 to 5 45 2 2
da biste dobili vaše pitanje i 4 do 5 45 2 2
85 88 that's true that's what he said
85 88 to je istina da je ono što je on rekao
that's what it is in code hidden code
to je ono što je u kodu skrivenog koda
you can also get us in the chat room at
možete nas i dobiti u sobi za razgovor
category 5 on freenode and of course
kategorija 5 na freenode i naravno
through our website category five dot TV
preko naše web stranice kategorije pet dot TV
so stick around we'll be right back with
zato se vrati, odmah ćemo se vratiti
all these exciting things coming up and
sve ove uzbudljive stvari dolaze i
your viewer questions don't go any
vaša pitanja gledalaca ne odlaze
right back this is category 5 technology
desno nazad je tehnologija kategorije 5
TV
TV
at eco alkalines we believe you should
u eko alkaline za koje verujemo da treba
be able to trust your batteries not just
biti u mogućnosti da verujete svojim baterijama ne samo
here but here here and here but with one
ovdje ali ovdje ovdje i ovdje, ali s jednom
exception you should also be able to
izuzetak koji bi takođe trebali biti u mogućnosti
trust your batteries here eco alkalines
vjeruj svojim baterijama ovdje eko alkaline
of the world's first and only certified
prvi i jedini certificirani na svijetu
carbon neutral battery manufactured to
ugljenično neutralna baterija proizvedena na
the highest standards of recycling and
najviše standarde recikliranja i
quality without any trace amounts of
kvaliteta bez tragova
harmful chemicals like mercury lead or
štetne hemikalije kao što su živo olovo ili
cadmium eco outlines provide performance
Kadmij eko linije pružaju performanse
the rivals leading national alkaline
rivali vodeći nacionalni alkalni
battery brands at a comparable price
marke akumulatora po uporedivoj cijeni
find out more about the Eco alkalines
saznajte više o Eko alkalinama
difference eco alkalines calm this is
razlika eko alkalini mirno je ovo
category 5 technology TV i'm your host
kategorija 5 tehnologija TV Ja sam vaš domaćin
Ravi Ferguson and I'm Eric Kidd I'm the
Ravi Ferguson i ja sam Eric Kidd
co-host by definition and how about a
Suorganizator po definiciji i kako o
big shout out through some of our new
veliki povik kroz neke od naših novih
registered viewers yeah Jay Blake 58 hey
registrirani gledatelji yeah Jay Blake 58 hej
hey and sifo and Bill 777 sifo bill 777
hej i sifo i Bill 777 sifo račun 777
nice rifle sifo yeah one person let me
lepa puška sifo yeah jedna osoba pustiti mene
know okay saying hi to both of you okay
Znam dobro govori hi oboma dobro
same time it's the thought your new
u isto vreme je misao vaše novo
thing the multitasking and we have J
stvar je multitasking i imamo J
voltage to two people j bolted j and
napon na dvije osobe j vijcima j i
manda BM man debian i bet is probably
manda BM čovjek debian i bet je vjerojatno
probably you know man debian man Devon
verovatno poznajete čoveka Debiana Devona
man debian but you know yeah well leaves
čovek debian ali znaš da dobro odlazi
like what you say like it's a syllabic
voli ono što kažeš kao da je silabik
stress being on the third last syllable
stres na trećem poslednjem slogu
it could be like beyond debian ooh i'm
moglo bi biti kao iza debian ooh ja sam
thinking as probably like man debian
Razmišljao je kao o čoveku debian
like a realization welcome nerdlings oh
kao realizacija dobrodošli nerdlings oh
and taco when hey taco one taco on i'll
i taco kada hej taco jedan taco na ja ću
say one you say when one of us to be
reci ono što kažeš kada neko od nas bude
right and they'll smile so can be duck
desno i oni će se nasmejati tako da mogu biti patke
struggling with this one em to be dumped
boreći se sa ovim da ih bace
be duck mped I gonna let him have that
Duck mped
one so please click and k-12 DOB
tako da molimo kliknite i k-12 DOB
and mem ito 64 and masterminds nice to
i mem ito 64 i masterminds lijepo to
have you all here joining us as new
da li nam se svi ovde pridružite kao novi
registered viewers on our website triple
registrirani gledatelji na našoj web stranici trostruki
w category 5 TV of course if you
w kategorija 5 TV naravno ako
register you get access to some really
Registrujte se da dobijete pristup nekim stvarno
cool bonus features on our website as
cool bonus značajke na našoj web stranici kao
well you'll be able to participate in
dobro ćete moći da učestvujete
prize draws and things that
nagradne igre i stvari koje
non-registered viewers are not able to
neregistrovani gledaoci nisu u mogućnosti
pay ability to wish the good participate
platite sposobnost da poželite dobro učešće
be like ah only I could participate in
biti kao ah samo ja mogu da učestvujem
this well now's your chance to go and
ovo je sada vaša šansa da idete
register on our website category 5 TV
registrujte se na našoj web stranici kategorije 5 TV
but Eric how much does that cost it's
ali Eric koliko to košta
pretty pricey it's gonna take you
prilično skupo će te odvesti
probably 20 seconds 30 seconds that's
verovatno 20 sekundi i 30 sekundi
all of your precious time time is money
svo vaše dragoceno vreme je novac
Eric it is hey I'm donating an hour or
Eric je da jesam donirao sat vremena
so here's magnet I want a ring I take
Evo magneta koji želim prsten koji uzmem
any water race oh I do have a gift for
za bilo koju vodenu utrku, imam dar za
you tonight then we'll talk about that
ti večeras ćemo pričati o tome
all right are all right you had a
sve je u redu da si imao
birthday recently didn't ya I didn't I
rođendan nedavno nisam
did I am down 35 dance hey dyslexic
jesam li pao na 35 ples hej dyslexic
don't forget to go to our web star
ne zaboravite otići na našu web-zvijezdu
mobile website if you've got a mobile
mobilni web sajt ako imate mobilni telefon
device scan that code mcat 5 TV we've
uređaj skenira taj kod mcat 5 TV
got live streaming they're both audio
imaju live streaming, oba su audio
and video at the same time but also i
i video u isto vrijeme, ali i
mean like separate you can just listen
znači kao odvojeni možete samo slušati
to the show if you want with category 5
u emisiju ako želite sa kategorijom 5
radio which is kind of cool quite
radio koji je prilično cool
frankly neither one of us is that good
iskreno, ni jedan od nas nije tako dobar
looking we have really good basis for
izgleda da imamo stvarno dobru osnovu za
radio as they say I in I'm gonna leave
radio kako kažu sam sam otići
that alone for now category five TV is a
to je samo za sada TV kategorija pet
member of the tech podcast network if
član tehnološke podcast mreže ako
it's tech it's here and at the
tehnologija je ovde i na
International Association of Internet
Međunarodno udruženje Interneta
broadcasters thanks Eric okay I
emiteri zahvaljuju Ericu u redu
mentioned a little bit of a we're going
spomenuo pomalo idemo
to be looking at some gadgets from
gledati neke gadgete od
rikomagic you mentioned rikomagic band
rikomagic ste spomenuli rikomagic bend
you mentioned episode 2 83 yeah well
spomenuli ste epizodu 2 83 yeah well
remember back on episode 283 we actually
Zapamtite nazad u epizodi 283 mi zapravo
looked at the remember yes easy sorry
pogledao je zapamti da je lako žao
yeah but yesterday was Canada Day stable
Da, ali juče je bio dan Kanade
I was on a gig happy canada day related
Bio sam na koncertu sretan dan u Kanadi
by the way it just fell in such a way
usput je samo pala na takav način
that here we are wishing you a belated
da vam ovde želimo zakašnjelo
canada day but for those of you in
kanada dan, ali za one od vas
America we can we can be proactive and
Amerika koju možemo, možemo biti proaktivni i
say happy fourth of July to you we're a
kažem vam srećan četvrti jul
little
malo
well we're a little yes that's
dobro smo malo da, to je
independence day is enough yes mmm yes
dan nezavisnosti je dovoljan da mmm da
very good your history is there you go
vrlo dobra tvoja istorija je tu
really impressive Eric part of the
zaista impresivan dio Erica
coming up with a sequel to that movie
dolazi sa nastavkom tog filma
too oh dear that's what it was sure okay
previše oh draga to je bilo sigurno
okay no we looked at this device cake
U redu , pogledali smo ovu tortu
let's let's get on track here just for a
hajdemo na stazu ovdje samo za
moment okay rikomagic this is the mini
trenutak u redu rikomagic ovo je mini
pc right so we looked at this bad boy
pc desno tako da smo pogledali ovog lošeg dečka
awesome stuff this one's still in the
strašne stvari, ovo je još uvek u
wrapper this one's brand new so this is
ovo je potpuno novi, tako da je ovo
the the bluetooth you know it's it's
Bluetooth koji znate da je to
actually a full computer and that's what
u stvari puni kompjuter i to je ono što
we looked at on episode number 2 83 so
pogledali smo na epizodi broj 2 83 tako
go check that out when we looked at this
idite provjerite kada smo pogledali ovo
device the reason that I pull that out
Razlog zbog kojeg sam to izvukao
is just so that you can remember what we
je samo tako da se možete sjetiti šta smo mi
were looking at that night so that is
gledali su te noći, tako da je tako
the mini PC but we needed a particular
mini PC ali nam je bio potreban poseban
type of USB hub to run that to remember
tip USB čvorišta za pokretanje tog zapamćenog
this thing this is the the newer
ovo je ovo noviji
technology 7 port USB hub it's a powered
tehnologija 7 port USB hub je napajanje
USB hub with its own power supply and
USB hub sa sopstvenim napajanjem i
everything I wonder how I could best
sve se pitam kako bih mogao najbolje
show it to you maybe if if Heather are
pokažite ga možda ako je Heather
you able to actually see if I hold that
možete da vidite da li to držim
up you can see that what's really
gore možete vidjeti ono što je stvarno
interesting about this device not only
zanimljiv samo o ovom uređaju
is it is you know it's a full hub but it
to je da znate da je to puna koncentrator ali to
also has a 2.1 amp dedicated power port
ima i 2.1 amp namjenski priključak za napajanje
that's what was really good for us when
to je bilo stvarno dobro za nas
we're using our rikomagic device because
koristimo naš rikomagički uređaj zato što
it gives dedicated power with no data
daje namjensku snagu bez podataka
connection to a computer anything is
veza sa računarom je sve
just straight power being generated by
samo pravom snagom se generiše
the newer technology hub powered haha so
noviji tehnološki čvor pokreće haha ​​tako
this is not just great for that I mean
ovo nije samo velika za to mislim
we found the perfect use for this device
Našli smo savršenu upotrebu za ovaj uređaj
but it is a seven port powered hub USB
ali to je USB port sa sedam portova
to point it is a fantastic device and it
pokazati da je to fantastičan uređaj i to
is high powered like this is 4 amps so
je visoko napajan kao što je ovo 4 ampera
you can charge your iPad off of this
možete napuniti svoj iPad
thing which and I the reason I use iPad
stvar koja i ja razlog zašto koristim iPad
or your blackberry well that that
ili vaša kupina dobro
doesn't the iPad draws a lot more
iPad ne crpi mnogo više
current like if you plug an iPad into a
trenutni kao ako priključite iPad na a
computer there's not enough current in
kompjuteru nema dovoljno struje
the computer to charge it right so you
kompjuter da ga napuni tako da vi
plug it into this and it's all of a
uključite ga u ovo i sve je to
sudden you've got you know 2.1 amp
odjednom ste saznali 2.1 amp
dedicated so this has got a lot of power
posvećena tako da ovo ima mnogo snage
behind it reason I wanted to bring this
iza toga sam hteo da donesem ovo
back up tonight is because we've got one
Vraćamo se večeras zato što ga imamo
to give away ah so I want to actually
poklanja ah tako da želim da zaista
send you one so pop me an email live at
poslat ću vam jednu e-mail poruku uživo
category 5
kategorija 5
TV if you're watching this you know on
TV ako gledate ovo što znate
demand if you're not able to watch the
zahtevajte ako ne možete da gledate
live show send me an email live at
live show pošalji mi e -poruku uživo na
category 5 TV tell me where you're from
Kategorija 5 TV mi reci odakle si
what your registered viewer name is
što je vaše registrirano ime gledatelja
because you've got to be registered on
zato što moraš biti registrovan
our site which is free as we mentioned
naš sajt koji je besplatan kao što smo spomenuli
and then we'll enter you into the draw
i onda ćemo ući u žreb
if you are going to be watching the show
ako ćeš gledati emisiju
live next week don't worry we're going
žive sledeće nedelje ne brinite da idemo
to have drama joining us in the chat
da nam se drama pridruži u razgovoru
room and he's going to go in grab all
i on će otići u sve
your names and draw but put you into the
Vaša imena i nacrtati, ali vas staviti u
draw so okay so that is that we're going
nacrtaj tako u redu tako da mi idemo
to send that anywhere in the world very
da pošaljemo to bilo gdje u svijetu vrlo
excited about that because it is a
uzbuđen zbog toga jer je to
excellent device okay i mentioned
odličan uređaj u redu sam spomenuo
rikomagic is is you did bring it out
rikomagic je da ste ga izvadili
some really cool yes new versions new
neke stvarno kul da nove verzije nove
upgrades we looked at I mean this this
Nadogradnje koje smo pogledali Mislim na ovo
bad boy is amazing we looked at this one
Loš momak je neverovatan kada smo pogledali ovaj
a little while ago yeah right they sent
malopre su ga poslali
me another box and said okay this one
ja još jednu kutiju i rekao sam dobro ovo
this when you're not hooking it up to it
ovo kada ga ne vezujete za to
I'm not hooking it up all right now this
Ne povezujem to sada
is a precursor to the hookup episode
je prethodnik epizode spajanja
where we're actually gonna set out we're
gde ćemo zapravo da krenemo
going to configure it and everything but
konfigurirati ga i sve drugo osim
not okay so first of all immediately you
nije u redu pa prvo odmah
notice that the box is about twice as
primetite da je kutija otprilike dva puta veća
big so you figure the things going to be
veliki tako da misliš da će stvari biti
twice as big you'd think that you'd
dvaput veći nego što mislite
think so apparently I'm betting you'd be
mislim da je tako očigledno da se kladim
wrong I'm bettin so here we go okay
Pogrešno sam bettin tako da idemo u redu
looks the same so it's about exactly the
Izgleda isto tako da se radi o tačno
same this is the 802 for a total to four
isto je i 802 za ukupno četiri
but the four is in Roman numerals so
ali četiri su rimskim brojevima tako
this is the 802 IV if you would say so
Ovo je 802 IV, ako vi tako kažete
yeah it's like an inner Venus vision so
Da, to je kao unutrašnja vizija Venere
this really be plugs you in with all the
ovo vas stvarno povezuje sa svim
awesomes there must be more goodies in
awesomes mora biti više dobrih stvari
the Box I bet you have to have some
Okvir Kladim se da moraš imati neke
unboxing music alright here it goes
unboxing muzika u redu ovde ide
Heather could you grab the guitar okay
Heather bi mogla da uzmeš gitaru u redu
no there's oh oh look at what they've
ne, oh, pogledaj šta su oni
thrown in for you okay we've got our ru
bačen u za li u redu da imamo naše ru
hdmi little an HDMI well because here if
hdmi malo HDMI dobro jer ovdje ako
you haven't seen the feature here's
niste videli tu mogućnost
what's cool about these it looks like oh
ono što je cool u ovome izgleda kao oh
not only the unboxing the unselfie Nina
ne samo unboxing Nino
can I take off the cellophane I think
mogu li skinuti celofan?
you can we asking permission or ability
možete tražiti dozvolu ili sposobnost
sir may i yes
Gospodine, mogu li da
me thank you grammar police okay so it
hvala vam gramatička policija u redu tako
looks like a USB flash drive right but I
izgleda kao USB fleš disk pravo ali ja
take this off and what is that but hdmi
skini ovo i šta je to, ali hdmi
full-sized hdmi so you can connect this
hdmi u punoj veličini tako da možete povezati ovo
directly into your HDTV alright so got
direktno na HDTV u redu tako dobio
the USB hub well that can power that
USB čvorište koje to može napajati
kind of power that is very good yeah
vrsta moći koja je vrlo dobra da
okay so let's open this up instead of it
U redu, hajde da otvorimo ovo umesto njega
I'm very sensitive oh this is beautiful
Veoma sam osetljiv
ok so the extender what this does ok is
ok tako da je ekstender ono što je u redu
it takes that hdmi and it makes it
potrebno je da hdmi to učini
longer so that if your TV for some
duže, tako da ako vaš TV za neke
reason is set up in such a way that you
Razlog je postavljen na takav način da vi
can't plug that directly into the back
ne može da se uključi direktno u leđa
because you know maybe the etching is
jer znate da je bakropis
there sir please you know yeah so this
gospodine, molim vas da znate da, tako da
allows you to in that case boom it still
dozvoljava vam da u tom slučaju i dalje bumirate
works on your TV and it just hangs off
radi na vašem TV-u i samo visi
the back it's a full computer I'm gonna
nazad je pun kompjuter koji ću
tell you the specs in a minute that's
reći ću ti naočare za minut
gonna blow your mind but look at what I
će ti raznijeti um, ali pogledaj šta ja
see in the box I'll show you whoa it
vidi u kutiji, pokazaću ti
came with an AC adapter they're thinking
došao je sa AC adapterom koji razmišljaju
and you know this could be after our
i znaš da bi ovo moglo biti nakon našeg
last review we said look we need to have
u poslednjem pregledu smo rekli da moramo imati pogled
a third-party adapter here because a
tu je adapter treće strane jer a
computer generally are partly
računar je uglavnom delimično
responsible for this Illinois am well
odgovoran za ovaj Ilinois je dobro
because a computer can't power the
jer kompjuter ne može napajati
rikomagic device because there's just
rikomagic uređaj jer postoji samo
like the iPad there's not enough am
kao i iPad nije dovoljno
pitch there right coming out of the
visina tamo pravo izlazi iz
computer so they're actually including a
kompjuter tako da oni zapravo uključuju a
device here that is going to plug it in
uređaj koji će ga uključiti
so there you go and now you can plug it
pa idite i sada ga možete uključiti
into the wall you're good to go and
u zid ti je dobro ići
there's also for those of you who want
postoji i za one koji žele
it there's a oh it's actually they've
to je oh, u stvari, oni su
included in a u.s. median and yeah a USB
uključen u nama medijan i da USB
mini to USB a adapter I think that's a
mini na USB adapter Mislim da je to
right that's cool that could actually be
pravo koje je kul to zapravo mogao biti
really really handy for a lot of things
Stvarno jako zgodan za mnoge stvari
another thing I would never understood
Još jedna stvar koju nikada ne bih shvatio
about usb being Universal yeah y ahora
o usb je univerzalni yeah y ahora
there's more than three different that's
ima ih više od tri
I didn't come in handy though because
Nisam, mada, nije mi dobro došao
how many times do you need to charge
koliko puta trebate naplatiti
your phone and you don't have a USB a
telefona i nemate USB a
totally now I so folks okay thats just
potpuno sada, tako mi je dobro
want to make sure that's you think
želim da budem siguran da misliš
that'll fit your black but i think it
to odgovara tvom crnom, ali mislim
might oh look if I foot is in Pearl
može li izgledati ako ja kročim u Pearl
check better look at that it will charge
proverite bolje pogledati da će se naplaćivati
your blackberry too sorry go there's a
vaša kupina je previše žao da je tu
charger for you back all right right in
punjač za vas, sve u redu
the box okay sweet deal
kutija u redu slatko
for those of you who use blackberrys oh
za one koji koriste kupine oh
those poor kids took another hit on Wall
ta jadna deca su ponovo udarila u zid
Street I know if they ever okay here it
Ulica znam da li je to ikada dobro
is this is the new model I told you that
je ovo novi model koji sam vam rekao
they've been upgrading and improving so
oni su se nadograđivali i poboljšavali
what do we got okay first of all it's
šta nam je prvo u redu?
Android jellybean 4.2 okay it's an
Android jellybean 4.2 u redu je
rk3188 quad-core processor this has a
rk3188 quad-core procesor ovo ima
quad-core CPU GPU built-in it's got to d
ugrađeni quad-core CPU GPU je dobio d
3d acceleration it's got 8 gigabytes ram
3d ubrzanje ima 8 gigabajta ram
up to 16 gigabytes ram built-in i guess
do 16 gigabajta ram ugrađeni pretpostavljam
that's an and memory like not not ram i
to je i memorija kao ne ram i
should say it's a it's the like the
treba da kaže da je to kao da je
actual storage storage space ok 2
stvarni skladišni prostor ok 2
gigabytes of RAM pardon me ddr3 and it's
gigabajta RAM pardon me ddr3 i to je
got it actually has a microSD port on
dobio je zapravo microSD port
the back here and with that micro SD you
nazad ovde i sa tim mikro SD-om
can put in up to 32 gigabytes of storage
može staviti do 32 gigabajta memorije
so if you want to add extra storage
ako želite dodati dodatni prostor za pohranu
space to it you got plenty of room for
prostor za to imate dovoljno mjesta
it it has built-in Wireless 802 11 BGN
ima ugrađeni Wireless 802 11 BGN
and there you go so they've basically
i eto ih u osnovi
taken it and it's quad-core while
uzela je i to je četvorojezgreni
screaming fast and because this is this
brzo vrišti i zato što je ovo ovo
is a standard ARM processor guess what
je standardni ARM procesor
we could put linux on this ah so that's
mogli bismo staviti linux na ovaj ah tako da je to
one of the experiments that we're going
jedan od eksperimenata koje idemo
to be doing out of the box like I say it
da radi out of the box kao što sam to reći
comes with Android 4.2 and now 4.2 is
dolazi sa Androidom 4.2 i sada je 4.2
also available for the original
dostupna je i za original
rikomagic mini pc so if you bought this
rikomagic mini pc pa ako ste ovo kupili
after seeing the review will actually be
nakon što pogledate recenziju će zapravo biti
showing you in an upcoming episode how
pokazuje vam u nadolazećoj epizodi kako
to upgrade to version 4.2 of android OS
za nadogradnju na verziju 4.2 Android OS-a
so that's going to be cool too okay
tako da će i to biti u redu
you're ready for more there's more come
spremni ste za još više
on let me cameraman he's still my
na pustiti mene kamermana on je još uvijek moj
beating heart do I sound like like a
Zvuči mi kao srce
absolute nerd like tella that didn't
apsolutni glupan kao tella koji nije
start tonight Robbie no okay hey I've
početi večeras Robbie nije u redu hej sam
got to show you this so the bald nerd
moram vam pokazati ovo tako ćelav glupan
moniker I know it's a lot of hair on the
Nadam se da znam da je puno kose na
side there rule this week what can I say
tamo vladaju ove nedelje šta da kažem
okay when you're when you're working
u redu kada radite
with your mini PC or any of these kinds
sa vašim mini PC-jem ili bilo kojom od ovih vrsta
of devices what's the thing you're okay
Uređaji su ono što je u redu
how do I want to control it and I have
kako želim da ga kontrolišem i imam
you know I've got the controller the air
znate da imam kontroler vazduha
mouse from my xios okay so that works
miš iz moje xios u redu tako da radi
really really well and I use that I've
stvarno jako dobro i koristim to što sam
also got an air mouse that that
takodje je dobio vazdušni miš
rikomagic this is their early model air
rikomagic ovo je njihov rani model zraka
mouse which we had previously used with
miš koji smo ranije koristili
the with the rikomagic mini PC okay but
s rikomagic mini PC u redu ali
watch what they're doing now oh okay air
gledaj šta sada rade
mouse meets television remote control
miš zadovoljava daljinski upravljač televizije
are we a universal no universal remote
mi smo univerzalni univerzalni daljinski upravljač
Holy Smoke dainty right it's got
Prekrasna prašnjavica ima pravo
everything on there that you'd ever want
sve što je ikada poželelo
TV VCRs left leg hair says that'll with
Televizijski videorekorderi kose lijeve noge kažu da će s njima
the TV and DVD player this works right
TV i DVD plejer to radi
okay so it's just a universal remote big
U redu, to je samo univerzalni daljinski
whoop it has a USB input can you see
koji ima USB ulaz možete vidjeti
that that USB input charged I see more
da je taj USB ulaz napunjen vidim više
he sees more the USB input charges the
on vidi više USB ulaza naplaćuje
built-in battery so you never have to
ugrađenu bateriju tako da nikada ne morate
change a remote battery again now are
ponovo promenite udaljenu bateriju
you ready let's turn this thing around a
spreman da okrenemo ovu stvar oko
full qwerty keyboard with directional
puna qwerty tastatura sa usmerenom
area arrows on the back of your
područje strelice na poleđini
multi-function remote this keyboard is
Višefunkcijski daljinski upravljač je ova tipkovnica
in fact bluetooth whoa
u stvari bluetooth whoa
you can use this with anything that
ovo možete koristiti sa bilo čim
supports bluetooth so you've got now you
podržava bluetooth tako da sada imate i vi
have that we finally have a remote
da konačno imamo daljinski
control that makes sense for our home
kontrola koja ima smisla za naš dom
theater PC regardless of whether you're
pozorište PC bez obzira da li ste
going with a rikomagic for your home
ide s rikomagic za vaš dom
theater PC whatever you have if it's got
pozorište PC šta god imate ako ima
bluetooth this is it so this is our most
bluetooth to je to tako da je ovo naš najveći
nor a keyboard and everything it's all
niti tastatura i sve što je sve
there and yes it has an air mouse
tamo i da ima vazdušni miš
built-in that so you can actually move
ugrađeni tako da se zapravo možete kretati
around like this you know I first
okolo kao što znate prvi
started working TV station they had
počeli su da rade TV stanicu koju su imali
these eunuchs terminals that and I set
ti terminali eunuha koji sam i postavio
them up with windows 95 was pretty cool
njih je sa prozorima 95 bilo prilično cool
and with nice and honest to goodness i'm
i sa finim i iskrenim prema dobroti
not exaggerating this one poor person
ne preuveličavati ovu siromašnu osobu
was their point holding the mouse up in
je njihova tačka držala miša unutra
the air trying to make it was especially
vazduh je pokušavao da to učini posebno
the cordless they were they were well no
oni koji su bili bežični bili su dobro ne
we didn't have cordless yet come on oh
još nismo imali bežični priključak oh
yes okay for that that's right it was
Da, u redu, to je tačno
nineteen ninety-two by with it okay
devedeset devedeset dva sa njim u redu
nobody got here I want to show you okay
Niko nije stigao ovde da ti pokažem
we've got a charger cable okay and also
imamo i punjač
the this is just the adapter adapter
ovo je samo adapter adaptera
your computer now receives the Bluetooth
računar sada prima Bluetooth
signal one is able to support this
signal jedan je u stanju da to podrži
remote little instruction manual and
daljinski mali priručnik s uputama i
there you have it I think that's the
Mislim da je to
perfect htpc remote what do you folks
savršen htpc daljinski što vi ljudi
think in the in the chat room so again
Razmislite ponovo u sobi za razgovor
this is looking amazing so our whole
ovo izgleda neverovatno tako da je naša celina
setup here yeah when you want next well
setup ovdje da kada želite sljedeći dobro
yeah cuz we want to actually hook this
yeah cuz želimo zapravo spojiti ovo
time thing this is probably not only is
vreme stvar je to verovatno ne samo
it a fabulous idea but I mean it's it's
to je fantastična ideja, ali mislim da je to
not particularly expensive no it's very
nije posebno skupo to je vrlo
gentle yeah it's amazingly cheap this
nežno je da je ovo neverovatno jeftino
stuff rikomagic calm i'm going to
rikomagic miru idem
actually bring up their website real
zapravo dovedu do stvarne web stranice
quick but i'm going to post links in the
brzo, ali ću da postavim linkove u
show notes for episode number 302 as
prikaži napomene za epizodu broj 302 kao
well okay so i just want to see if I
Pa dobro, samo želim da vidim
still have a short link there yeah Rico
još uvijek ima kratku vezu tamo da Rico
it's cat five dot TV / mini PC and that
to je TV / mini PC sa pet tačaka i to
is actually going to take you to their
zapravo će vas odvesti do njihovih
website you can see some of the amazing
web stranice možete vidjeti neke od nevjerojatnih
stubble they're coming up Vinnie yeah a
čekinje dolaze do Vinnie da je
webcam with a built-in while rikomagic
web kamera sa ugrađenim dok je rikomagic
type device so you'll find all this
upišite uređaj tako da ćete sve to pronaći
stuff they're all of the pricing is
stvari koje su sve cijene su
available to you and they're shipping
koje su vam dostupne i isporučuju se
worldwide right now so that stuff is
širom svijeta sada, tako da stvari postoje
available to you
na raspolaganju
cap five dot TV / mini pc is the best
kapica pet tačaka TV / mini pc je najbolja
thing ever fantastic so is the remote
ono što je fantastično tako je i daljinski
well so are these all available
Pa, tako su i sve to dostupne
separately yes okay yeah and there's the
odvojeno da dobro u redu da i tu je
remote this is the MK 702 Roman numerals
daljinski to su MK 702 rimske brojke
to soho 7022 are there other models
na soho 7022 postoje drugi modeli
available of the remote not this one
na raspolaganju za daljinski ne ovaj
this is this is the remote that you want
ovo je ovo ono što želite
to get for sure you'll find it all on
sigurno ćete naći sve na sebi
rikomagic we're not going to get into
rikomagic nećemo ući u
pricing and stuff and because all that
cijene i stvari i zato sve to
stuff is being you know put up on their
stvari se znaju staviti na svoje
website but when you watch the the
ali kada gledate
website category 5 TV and we're going to
website category 5 TV i mi ćemo
be announcing when we're actually going
najavljujemo kada idemo
to be conducting a full review of these
da izvrši potpunu reviziju ovih
products in which case you know at that
proizvode u tom slučaju znate
point we're going to actually be firing
mislim da ćemo zapravo pucati
things up we're going to be running
stvari će se pokrenuti
everything showing you what happens on
sve vam pokazuje ono što se dešava na
the screen just like we did an episode
ekran kao što smo uradili epizodu
for 283 with the other product and we're
za 283 sa drugim proizvodom i mi smo
going to show you how everything
pokazaću ti sve
connects and how to how to make it work
povezuje i kako to učiniti
so but they are very affordable as Eric
tako da su veoma pristupačne kao Eric
was saying so check it out cat five dot
govorio je tako da pogledaj mačku pet tačaka
TV / mini PC all one word this is
TV / mini PC sve ovo je jedna riječ
category 5 technology TV I'm Robbie
kategorija 5 tehnologija TV Ja sam Robbie
Ferguson and the American it's a viewer
Ferguson i Amerikanac je gledalac
question extravaganza tonight so we get
pitanje ekstravaganca večeras, tako da ćemo dobiti
right into it I think we should do a
mislim da bi trebali da uradimo
couple questions before we jump into the
par pitanja pre nego što skočimo u
news and then we'll come back to your
a onda ćemo se vratiti na vašu
questions as well don't forget our our
pitanja takođe ne zaboravite naše
cat phone as we call it the telephone
mačji telefon kako ga zovemo telefon
here in the studio is open to you if
ovde u studiju je otvoren za vas ako
you'd like to give us a call to 5 45 228
želite da nam daju poziv na 5 45 228
588 that's basically 255 calf five TV so
To je u suštini 255 telećih pet televizora
there that's all right way evidence we
to je sve što možemo da dokažemo
have a question from Steve hey Steve
Imam pitanje od Steve hey Steve
Steve says you could show how to hook up
Steve kaže da možeš pokazati kako se povezati
a VGA or an hdmi cable from a laptop to
VGA ili HDMI kabl od laptopa do
TV I did this with my new 220 dollar LED
TV To sam uradio sa mojim novim 220 dolarskim LED-om
32 inch TV 720p screen excellent as a
32-inčni TV ekran 720p odličan kao
monitor huge and beautiful I'll vga em
monitor ogroman i lijep ću vga em
/em cord cost me only ten dollars at
košta me samo deset dolara
microcenter old editions of it Linux
microcenter stara izdanja Linuxa
reset resolution to 13 60 x 768 new ones
resetirajte rezoluciju na 13 60 x 768 novih
sets it automatically secretly I think
postavlja se automatski potajno mislim
they're over
završili su
pricing on some chords price-fixing
određivanje cijena na nekim akordima
perhaps if you go as large the screen as
možda ako odete na veliki ekran kao
you want great for watching videos and a
želite odličan za gledanje videa i a
cat5 TV great idea it worked for Steve
cat5 TV odlična ideja da je radio za Stevea
there you go Steve ya know if you can
Eto, znaš, Steve znaš da li možeš
get a cheap cable okay so I'll tell you
uzmi jeftin kabel, pa ću ti reći
the difference between so that's a vga
razlika između tako je vga
male to male like just a monitor cable
muški i muški poput kabla za monitor
basically so an output from a laptop or
u suštini je to izlaz iz laptopa ili
a desktop computer going out to your H
stoni računar koji izlazi na vaš H
like your HDTV the disadvantage to the
kao što je vaš HDTV nedostatak
9-pin you know the blue adapter kpa
9-pin znate plavi adapter kpa
cable as you say is that its analog so
kabl kao što kažete je da je njegov analogni tako
you're getting a signal that is not as
dobijate signal koji nije takav
good of quality as the HDMI so if you
dobar kvalitet kao HDMI tako da ako
have the option output from HDMI that's
imate opciju izlaz iz HDMI to je
the one you want to go with because then
onaj sa kojim želiš da ideš , jer onda
you're going to have true digital HD
imat ćete pravi digitalni HD
video if you're going with D Sub the
video ako idete sa D Sub
9-pin a kind of cable you're going to
9-polna vrsta kabla koji ćete koristiti
lose signal quality and that could also
gube kvalitet signala i to bi moglo
be why it's detecting the the erroneous
zašto je to otkrivanje pogrešnog
screen resolution because you're
rezolucija ekrana jer ste
connecting it to a TV not to a computer
povezivanje sa televizorom ne na računar
monitor and so it's not a plug-and-play
monitor i to nije plug-and-play
device necessarily the computer sees
uređaj obavezno vidi računar
that it's there but probably can't quite
da je tu, ali verovatno ne može
tell what the device is and what its
reći šta je uređaj i šta je njegov
specs are like a computer monitor which
specifikacije su kao kompjuterski monitor koji
really feeds back a lot of data through
zaista se vraća mnogo podataka
the cable to the to the the computer so
kabl do računara
go with HDMI if you can our tables price
idite sa HDMI-om ako možete da platite naše stolove
fixed and overpriced you are seriously I
fiksiran i precijenjen ti si ozbiljno ja
mean you walk into a supercenter you
znači da uđete u supercentar
pick 10 bucks for a vga cable and you
pokupite 10 dolara za vga kabel i vi
know no big deal but you go in and it
ne znaju mnogo, ali vi ulazite i to
just price out a 50 foot hdmi cable or
samo isplati 50mm hdmi kabl ili
25 foot hdmi cable and you'll realize
25-metarski hdmi kabl i shvatit ćete
pretty quick even even better would be
prilično brzo čak i bolje
think about a category 5 or a category 6
razmislite o kategoriji 5 ili kategoriji 6
networking cable just grab a prefab one
kabl za umrežavanje samo zgrabite prefabrikovani
from a store and you'll realize how
iz prodavnice i shvatićeš kako
overpriced it is because you know
precijenjen je zato što znate
there's so many middlemen and their
ima toliko posrednika i njihovih
prefabricated up there you know the cost
prefabrikovani tamo znate cijenu
of a cable might be a buck or two to the
kabla može biti jedan ili dva dolara
the people who are selling it so you
ljudi koji su ga prodaje, tako da
know if they're charging you forty fifty
znam da li vam naplaćuju četrdeset pedeset
dollars for the cable but not everybody
dolara za kabl, ali ne svi
has the tools and the email don't have
ima alate i e-mail nema
little ones together yeah but you you
djeca zajedno, ali vi
know if you're looking for cables that
znate da li tražite kablove
can
može
be manufactured on your own go into like
biti proizvedeni sami
an oem store that can make cables go
oem dućan koji može napraviti kablove
into an electronic store and say you
u elektronsku radnju i kažem vam
know can you make me a cable you we have
znaš, možeš li mi napraviti kabel koji imamo
spools of indicate when will cut off a
špulice ukazuju kada će odseći a
length and that's what the couple's
dužina i to je ono što je par
about a great little store sells in a
o velikoj maloj trgovini koja se prodaje u a
barrier know where ya doing the
barijera zna gde radite
commercial spot but called sale ok all
komercijalno mjesto, ali se zove prodaja ok sve
the little connectors and get like thing
male konektore i dobijam kao stvar
you can like the overview of taxes yeah
može vam se svideti pregled poreza
it's like yeah but way more than I'm
to je kao da, ali mnogo više nego ja
finding it at the source no the sources
pronalaženje na izvoru nema izvora
is not what it was when I was a kid and
nije ono što je bilo kad sam bio klinac
I say no riddle said I definitely did
Kažem da nijedna zagonetka nije definitivno
radio shack when Radio Shack was radio
radio koliba kada je Radio Shack bio radio
shack back in the 80s you could go in
vratite se u osamdesete u kojima možete ući
and it was like it was my dream because
i kao da je to bio moj san jer
I was building i was talking to back of
Gradila sam sam razgovarao sa zadnje strane
the other night about how i used to
pre neko veče o tome kako sam navikla
build patch panels audio patch panels
Izrada patch panela audio patch panela
from little parts that i bought for a
od malih delova koje sam kupio za
bucket radio shack and that was so
to je bilo tako
awesome and the fellow behind the
strašan i momak iza
counter was a retired electronics guy so
brojač je bio penzionisani elektroničar
he like it will be this way around i
voli da će biti ovako oko i
know what you got to do is it lives
Znaš šta treba da uradiš je da živi
anyway it was just nice little fun
u svakom slučaju, bilo je samo malo zabave
that's cool well i'll check that i
to je u redu i ja ću provjeriti da sam
pleased nice well i am I gonna do you
drago mi je što sam dobro uradio
know we've got something I gotta bring
znam da imamo nešto što moram donijeti
up to you yeah you're gonna have to
Na vama je da ćeš morati
bring this up alright so if you bring
donesi ovo, pa ako ti doneseš
that up working on Pyro's rock this
da radim na Pyro-ovom kamenu
world pyrus rock yes haha just received
world pyrus rock da haha upravo je primio
this thought you might add it to your
tu misao možete dodati u svoj
collection excellent okay I'm just going
kolekcija odlična u redu sam samo idem
to save this to my desktop here pires
da ovo sačuvam na moj desktop ovde pires
rock we like to protect your email
rock mi želimo zaštititi vašu e-poštu
address if we can yeah so oh nice so
adresu ako možemo da tako oh lijepo
this is an email i guess that has come
ovo je email koji pretpostavljam da je došao
into tip iris rock or viewer there we go
na vrh iris rock ili gledalac tamo idemo
google 15th anniversary reward center
google 15th birthday nagradni centar
it's a it's an anniversary award its
to je nagrada za jubilej
seemingly from google makes it look like
naizgled iz google čini izgledati
it's from google you know what's
to je od Google-a, znate šta je
interesting about this and and you may
zanimljivo o ovome i možeš
not immediately pick up on the
ne odmah pokupiti na
subtleties that these scammers and
suptilnosti koje ti prevaranti i
phishing scams try to use to trick you
phishing prevare pokušavaju da vas prevare
into thinking that this is legit the
u razmišljanje da je ovo legalno
first thing stands out to me is that it
Prva stvar koja mi se ističe je da je to
says google betta and
kaže google betta i
and it says what does it say right above
i piše šta kaže gore
that it says ssl so you you kind of and
da piše ssl, tako da ste vi vrsta i
it has the little lock so you kind of in
ima malu bravu, tako da ti se nekako uklapaš
your head think oh this is this is
tvoja glava misli da je ovo ovo
secure it's email all right you nothing
siguran da je e-mail sve u redu ti ništa
is secure through email regardless but
je sigurno putem e-pošte bez obzira na to
interestingly enough so but isn't that
interesantno, ali nije to
neat that they you know that don't fall
uredno da znaju da ne padaju
for that folks there you go so you want
za one ljude tamo idete tako da želite
a prize congratulations and it looks
čestitam nagradu i izgleda
pretty official and an email with a
prilično službeno i e-mail sa
handwritten signature is always official
rukopisni potpis je uvek zvaničan
you can tell interesting thankfully not
možete reći zanimljivo, na sreću ne
all that to say you know pires rock this
sve to da kažete da znate da pire ovo skaču
world sent that in for those viewers who
svet je to poslao za one gledaoce koji
are looking to that one or and what does
gledate na to ili na ono što
it mean companies usually won't you know
to znači da kompanije obično ne znaju
they won't solicit you by email like
neće vas tražiti putem e-pošte
that but hackers if you will we'll call
ali hakeri, ako hoćete, pozvat ćemo
them hackers just because that's the
oni hakeri samo zato što je to
generic term that's been applied to them
generički termin koji je primenjen na njih
will use company branding from companies
će koristiti brendove kompanija od kompanija
that you possibly trust in your bank are
koje možda imate povjerenja u svoju banku
here google how often you get something
ovdje google koliko često dobijate nešto
from a bank and it all looks legit
iz banke i sve izgleda legitimno
unless you actually run your your mouse
osim ako ne pokrenete miš
over top of the email link and you
preko linka e-pošte i vas
realizes 2xw why is Q rt.com off
ostvaruje 2xw zašto je Q rt.com isključen
somewhere and it's not really going to
negde i to stvarno neće
RVC your TD wherever you know and they
RVC svoj TD gdje god znate i oni
want your in from anger s you know
želiš da ti se javiš od besa koji znaš
social insurance number it's like it
broj socijalnog osiguranja to je kao da
always is meant to look really official
uvek je značilo da izgleda stvarno zvanično
right so you got to be really really
tako da moraš biti stvarno stvarno
careful of what what you reply to and
pazite na ono što odgovarate i
your email and what you what you click
Vašu e-poštu i ono što vi kliknete
on what links you go through in this
na koje veze prolazite kroz ovo
particular case it looks like they're
u konkretnom slučaju izgleda kao da su
not even getting you to really click on
ni dobiti da zaista kliknete na
links what they're trying to get you to
povezuje ono na šta pokušavaju da te navedu
do is to fill in the blanks provide what
da je ispuniti praznine pružiti ono što
your full name your country your contact
Vaše puno ime i ime vaše zemlje
address your telephone number your fax
adresu svog telefonskog broja faksom
number your occupation your sex and your
broj vaše zanimanje svoj seks i vaše
age so with that information I mean if
Izrazite sa tim informacijama, mislim ako
if I had that amount of information
ako imam tu količinu informacija
about somebody I'm pretty sure I don't
O nekome sam prilično siguran da ne znam
get a passport I could be done I could
mogu dobiti putovnicu koju bih mogao napraviti
have come to you yeah so this is
Došao sam k vama da jeste
probably an identity theft at
verovatno krađa identiteta
mped so you want to watch out for that
mped tako da želite paziti na to
kind of stuff for sure alright thanks
neke stvari sigurno, hvala
for sending that in mr. Philip brenson
za slanje u mr. Philip Brenson
and thank you for the email susan yes
i hvala vam za email susan da
okay here's a question from Jay read hey
ok evo pitanja od Jay čitati hej
jay is there any easy ways to use
jay postoji bilo koji jednostavan način korištenja
encryption on users shares that reside
šifriranje na korisničkim dionicama koje se nalaze
on an unrated server know very very
na neimenovanom serveru znam vrlo jako
complicated just like everything that I
komplikovan kao i sve što ja
show you we want to make it as hard as
pokažite nam da želimo da to bude teško
possible I'm detecting a slight hint of
moguće je da otkrijem malu naznaku
sarcasm I guess since you asked so
sarkazam pretpostavljam otkad si to pitao
nicely when they ugly go for that I mean
Lijepo kad su ružno išli za to mislim
can we go for easy encryption okay first
Možemo li prvo lakše šifrirati
of all unraid is a server platform for
of all unraid je serverska platforma za
hosting multiple hard drives in a single
hostovanje više čvrstih diskova u jednom
physical box so I've got a computer on
fizička kutija tako da imam računar
the network that has seven or eight hard
mreža koja ima sedam ili osam teško
drive so now I have the capacity of
vozim tako da sada imam kapacitet
basically six or seven hard drives in
u osnovi šest ili sedam tvrdih diskova
that with one extra hard drive for
za jedan dodatni hard disk
redundancy so if one failed I don't lose
redundancija, tako da ako neko ne uspe, ne gubim
my data great little server setup but
moji podaci veliki mali server setup ali
can you encrypt it I would want to ask
možete li ga šifrirati?
myself before I answer that question
prije nego što odgovorim na to pitanje
then the answer is yes okay I answered
onda je odgovor da, dobro sam odgovorio
it sorry but the fact is over well it's
žao mi je, ali činjenica je da je dobro
an in-house server so the only person
interni server tako da je jedina osoba
that we've kind of touched on this
da smo se nekako dotakli ovoga
before but if you encrypt something that
ali ako šifrujete nešto to
is only accessible to you anyways then
tada je dostupan samo vama
the only person that you are basically
jedina osoba koju ste u osnovi
encrypting against is yourself if
šifriranje protiv sebe jeste
somebody if somebody breaks and want his
nekoga ako neko razbije i želi svoj
wife to see his data but she would
ženu da vidi njegove podatke, ali ona bi
because it's on the server and so if
jer je na serveru i tako
somebody were to physically come in and
neko je trebao fizički ući i
steal your server they would fire it up
ukradi server koji će ga ispaliti
and they would have an unencrypted a bit
i imali bi malo nekodiran
because even if it was encrypted they
jer čak i ako su šifrirani
would have the ability to boot up the
bi imao mogućnost da pokrene sistem
whole thing and it would be readable if
čitava stvar i to bi bilo čitljivo ako
I encrypted it though then the Senate
Šifrirao sam ga iako u Senatu
the scenario is if somebody stole a
scenario je ako je neko ukrao
single hard drive from
jedan tvrdi disk
that drive would not be readable because
taj pogon neće biti čitljiv jer
it's no longer a part of the array which
to više nije deo niza koji
also decrypt the data for readability so
također dešifriraju podatke za čitljivost tako
who am i protecting it against the the
ko je ja štitim protiv
problem is is then okay so let's say you
Problem je u tome je onda u redu pa da ti kažeš
have a catastrophic failure and five of
imaju katastrofalan neuspjeh i pet
your 7 hard drives fail so you take
Vaših 7 tvrdih diskova ne možete tako prihvatiti
those hard drives because you no longer
Te tvrde diskove zato što više ne
have parity because the more than one
imaju paritet jer je više od jednog
drive failed it was a power surge say
pogon nije uspio, to je bio snažan udar
and you take those drives to data
a te pogone odnesete na podatke
recovery and you say okay well here are
oporavak i vi kažete dobro ovdje su
the five drives that have failed and I
pet pogona koji su propali i ja
need to get the data off of them and
trebate dobiti podatke od njih i
they'll say okay yeah we could get the
oni će reći u redu da možemo dobiti
data off but it's encrypted so we're not
podatke sa ali šifrovan tako da nismo
going to be able to read any of that
moći ću da pročitam bilo šta od toga
data know what now what exactly so with
podaci znaju šta sada tačno ima
this encrypted right now we've basically
ovo je sada šifrirano
caused a really risky scenario so I'm
izazvao je veoma rizičan scenario, tako da sam ja
just trying to think of a scenario where
samo pokušavam da smislim scenario gde
it would be necessary to encrypt a non
bilo bi neophodno šifrirati ne
raid array because it's an in-house
raid array jer je to in-house
server is not world accessible it's not
server nije dostupan svijetu nije
accessible by anyone except those who
pristupačan bilo kome osim onih koji
are in my network connected to my
su u mojoj mreži povezani sa mojom
network it's kind of like you know I've
mreža je kao da znate da sam
got you know thirty five hundred dollar
Znate trideset pet stotina dolara
Martin guitar mmm it has a little lock
Martin gitara mmm ima malu bravu
for it yeah on the case yeah what I'm
za to da na slučaju yeah ono što sam
gonna take the case but anybody's gonna
će uzeti slučaj, ali bilo ko će
steal the guitar is gonna I'm not gonna
ukrasti gitaru jer neću
open the case and take the guitar
otvori kutiju i uzmi gitaru
exactly know basically all that's for
tačno znam u suštini sve što je za
keeping your kids out of the case may be
držati djecu van slučaja
you know it's not really gonna protect
znaš da to stvarno neće štititi
the guitar from anything accidentally
od gitare slučajno
opening yeah that's about it okay so all
otvaranje da, to je sve u redu
that said I wouldn't mind hearing from
to je govorilo da mi ne bi smetalo da čujem
you what what your reasoning and thought
šta vi mislite i razmišljate
it processes behind wanting to encrypt
procesira iza željenog šifriranja
you want to do this why do you want to
želite to učiniti zašto želite
encrypt a nun raid array why you gotta
šifrirati niz časnih redova zbog čega moraš
be like that why you gonna do this man
Budi takav zašto ćeš uraditi ovog čoveka
why you got to do this uh okay there are
zašto moraš ovo uh dobro postoje
no I'm gonna touch on the question like
Ne, dotaknut ću pitanje
that's that you are still doubt my
to je da vi još uvek sumnjate u moju
response but also its pretty long
ali i prilično dugo
preamble to I'm sorry going into okay
preambula za žao mi je što se okrećem
sorry sorry for trying to be helpful
Žao mi je zbog pokušaja da budem od pomoći
sound a little negative i thought well i
zvuči malo negativno i dobro sam mislio
want you to know the risks if i'm going
Želim da znaš rizike ako idem
to do something that could risk the
da uradi nešto što bi moglo da rizikuje
integrity of my data in an event of a
integritet mojih podataka u slučaju a
catastrophic
katastrofalno
failure without any positive benefits
neuspjeh bez ikakve pozitivne koristi
than I want you two to know that to the
nego želim da vas dvojica to znate
left for your phone you know I hate when
ostavljen za vaš telefon znate da mrzim kada
that happens cuz you plugged in i am
to se dešava zato što sam uključen
sure and i see it i could actually say I
siguran sam i vidim da sam zapravo mogao reći I
think it's somebody from the studio I'm
mislim da je to neko iz studija
gonna turn my phone off there's an idea
isključiću telefon, postoji ideja
ah he's new here oh wait a minute no
Ah, on je novi ovdje
he's not ok so the of course to encrypt
nije u redu, naravno da šifrira
you you probably use en CFS like encrypt
vi verovatno koristite en CFS kao šifriranje
the file system which is coming
sistem datoteka koji dolazi
available with unraid version 5 which i
dostupan sa verovanom verzijom 5 koja i
understand is in betta and I'm I'm
razumem je u betta i ja sam
really so you know I like to use the
stvarno tako da znate da volim da koristim
stable version so I'm on 4.7 version 5
stabilna verzija, tako da sam na 4.7 verziji 5
though is is coming along quite nicely
iako je to prilično lijepo
and i'll give you the link to this
i daću vam vezu sa ovim
episode number 302 it'll be in the show
epizoda broj 302 biće u emisiji
notes quick link for you is cat five dot
bilješke brzi link za vas je mačka pet točka
TV / enc and you see that there is that
TV / enc i vidite da postoji to
will just take you right to the
samo ću vas odvesti pravo na
encryption section here and you see
sekcija enkripcije ovde i vidite
unraid five has the Encke FS plugin and
unraid 5 ima Encke FS plugin i
that basically will provide what you're
koji će u osnovi pružiti ono što ste vi
looking for encryption on your own raid
u potrazi za enkripcijom na vlastitoj raciji
device there's also a there's a neat way
Uređaj ima i uredan način
to do it is to actually install
to je zapravo instalacija
something but on your SATA bus which
nešto, ali na vašem SATA busu koji
would allow you to use an actual key
bi vam omogućio da koristite pravi ključ
lock which would have an encrypted and
zaključavanje koje bi imalo šifrovano i
decryption kind of thing going on so
dešifrovanje se dešava tako
still have you end up with your scenario
još uvek imaš svoj scenario
five or six drives down den de lo yeah
pet ili šest vozi dole
and critic asya a lot of trouble that
i kritičara asya mnogo problema
that way so yeah it's a hard call but
tako da, da, to je težak poziv, ali
does it send me a follow-up email and
šalje mi e-poštu za praćenje i
let me know why you why you hopeful do
reci mi zašto si se nadao
that and go from there hope that at
da i odatle idemo u nadu
least gives you some information but cat
najmanje vam daje neke informacije, ali mačka
five dot TV / e NC and that will that
pet tačaka TV / e NC i to će to
will take you to a forum thread that
će vas odvesti na forum forum
gives you a whole bunch of information
daje vam gomilu informacija
about how to encode or encrypt I should
o tome kako se kodira ili šifriranje bih trebala
say on an unread alright go
reći na neproitanu dobro go
but why we do news folks okay hers was
ali zašto radimo novosti u redu je njena bila
it more question let's do news and then
to je više pitanje, hajde da uradimo vesti i onda
questions all right let's do it here the
sva pitanja, hajde da to uradimo ovde
top stories from the category 5 TV news
top priče iz TV vijesti kategorije 5. \ t
room not the way of boosting data rates
prostor nije način povećanja brzine prenosa podataka
an optical communication using twisted
optičku komunikaciju pomoću upletene
light has been shown to work in optical
pokazalo se da svjetlo radi u optičkom svjetlu
fibers the light is effectively
svjetlo je učinkovito
corkscrew-shaped and more data can be
u obliku vadičice i više podataka može biti
encoded in differently twisted beams the
kodiran u različito uvijene grede
concept had previously be shown had been
Koncept je ranije bio prikazan
shown off over free space but it
prikazan iznad slobodnog prostora, ali to
remained unclear if would work in fibers
ostalo je nejasno da li će raditi u vlaknima
but now a team reporting in science has
ali sada tim izveštava u nauci
demonstrated data rates of 1.6 terabytes
pokazali brzine prenosa podataka od 1,6 terabajta
per second over one kilometer of optical
po sekundi preko jednog kilometra optičkog
fiber this is still short of the
vlakana to je još uvijek kratak je
over-the-air rate of two point five
over-the-air stopa od dvije točke pet
terabytes per second demonstrated by
terabajtova po sekundi prikazano
members of the same team in 2012 care
članovi istog tima u 2012. godini
about his Turbots I had to Freud that is
o njegovim Turbotima koje sam imao do Freuda
a small be there I did not I did not
malen biti tamo nisam ja nisam
correct kilometer but i have to the geek
pravilan kilometar, ali moram na geek
in me has to correct that it is terabits
u meni mora ispraviti da su to terabiti
2.5 terabits a second how would you
2.5 terabita u sekundi kako biste vi
correct kill me two kilometer it's
Ispravite me ubiju dva kilometra je to
that's incorrect kill 0 equals syllabic
to je netačno ubiti 0 jednako slogovno
stress it would like didn't with my says
stres bi volio da nije sa mojim riječima
I didn't correct we've lost this fight
Nisam ispravio da smo izgubili tu borbu
in the media terabyte kilometer and a
u terabajtnom kilometru medija i a
thermometer it that should be a gauge
termometar koji bi trebao biti mjerilo
for measuring something killough
za merenje nečeg ubogog
kilogram killem yeah okay tenth you
kilogram killem da dobro desetina ti
wouldn't say a cool kilo all equalto
ne bi rekao kul sve jednako
meter as you say a killer leader yes you
metar kao što kažete ubica vođa da vi
wouldn't say kilometer maybe I met if
ne bih rekao kilometar možda sam sreo ako
I'd had a couple of them oh it's just
Imao sam par njih
you know you ended up with a terabyte
znate da ste završili sa terabajtom
the americas got all of a terabyte and a
Americi je sve terabajt i
terrace allston terabit is a completely
terasa allston terabit je potpuno
different thing out that was absolutely
druga stvar koja je apsolutno bila
a different animal I'm getting the bike
druga životinja dobijam bicikl
totally totally different thing totally
potpuno totalno drugačija stvar
different thing i will give you that but
druga stvar koju ću ti dati, ali
either way that's what i did not correct
u svakom slučaju to je ono što nisam ispravio
you when you said who instead of whom
kada ste rekli ko umesto koga
earlier so um can we get back to the
ranije, tako da se možemo vratiti na
news let's do it
novosti učinimo to
so let's see this is still short of the
pa da vidimo da je ovo još uvek kratko
over-the-air rate of 2.5 terabits per
prosečna stopa od 2,5 terabita po
second demonstrated by members of the
drugi demonstrirani od strane članova
same team in 2012 but it is a powerful
isti tim u 2012, ali je moćan
proof of principle for adapting the
dokaz principa prilagođavanja
technique to use with fibrin data
tehnika za upotrebu sa podacima o fibrinu
centers I think all in all it's it's
Mislim da je sve u svemu
fast are we having fun yet yeah facebook
brzo se zabavljamo još da facebook
not again yes Facebook has rewarded a
ne opet da Facebook je nagradio a
British man with twenty thousand dollars
Britanac sa dvadeset hiljada dolara
that's about 13,000 pounds after he
to je oko 13.000 funti nakon njega
found a bug which could have exploited
pronašao grešku koja je mogla da iskoristi
to have been exploited to hack into
da su eksploatisani da bi upali
users accounts Jack Whitten the security
korisnički računi Jack Whitten sigurnost
researcher discovered the flaw in the
istraživač je otkrio manu u
social networks text messaging system
sistem za razmjenu tekstualnih poruka na društvenim mrežama
Facebook thank mr. wytton with 22 who is
Facebook hvala mr. Wytton sa 22 ko je
part of the sites responsible disclosure
deo sajta odgovornog otkrivanja
Hall of Fame the company like many on
Hall of Fame je kompanija kao i mnogi dalje
the web encourages experts to report
web ohrabruje stručnjake da izvještavaju
bugs to them rather than cyber criminals
greškama za njih nego za cyber kriminalce
I wonder like if I were to report you
Pitam se da li da vas prijavim
know the bugs that I encounter day today
poznajem greške koje se danas susreću
if I could get you know a portion of
ako bih mogao da te upoznam sa delom
that I don't know or do they spit don't
da ne znam ili ne pljuju
buddy how to do I I hate even go there
drugar kako da radim II mrzim čak i tamo
with this but you know are the
sa ovim, ali znate da su
cybercriminals gonna say yeah they gave
sajber kriminalci će reći da su dali
him 20 thousand what if we offered 25
njemu 20 hiljada šta ako ponudimo 25
what if we offer oh yeah imagine what
šta ako ponudimo oh da zamislite šta
you could do with with all that yeah
sa svim tim bi mogao
data okay come on keep it on it's not
podaci su u redu, držite ga na tome nije
the Facebook is ever compromised
Facebook je kompromitovan
microsoft research has suggested that
Microsoftovo istraživanje je to predložilo
they are ma during tube computer viruses
oni su u toku virusnih kompjuterskih virusa
which collaborate together to spread
koji zajedno sarađuju da bi se proširili
each other through networks and are
međusobno preko mreža i jesu
proving hard clean from infected pcs the
dokazivanje čvrstog čišćenja od zaraženih komada
pair of viruses foiled removal by
par virusa je uklonjen
regularly downloading updated versions
redovno skidanje ažuriranih verzija
of their malware partner they are using
njihovog malware partnera kojeg koriste
unknown to antivirus programs which let
nepoznat antivirusnim programima koji dozvoljavaju
the malicious programs persist once
zlonamerni programi traju jednom
present on a pc the viruses let thieves
prisutan na pc virusa neka lopovi
take over a machine so it can be mined
preuzmite mašinu tako da se može minirati
for saleable data or used to send spam
za podatke koji se mogu prodati ili koji se koriste za slanje neželjene pošte
or to attack other machines the close
ili da napadne druge mašine blizu
relationship between the two viruses was
odnos između dva virusa je bio
revealed in a blog spot by young choi
razotkrivena u blogu od strane mladih ljudi
from microsoft mount where research hmmm
od microsoft mount gdje se hmmm istražuje
that is something so they're getting
to je nešto što dobijaju
smart aren't they okay so the saying
pametni nisu oni u redu, tako govoreći
this is hard to detect etcetera etcetera
to je teško otkriti itd. itd
etc so what about the folks from
itd, pa šta je sa ljudima iz
je said or knows right I'm not familiar
je rekao ili zna da nisam upoznat
with the particular virus but I think
sa određenim virusom, ali mislim
the idea is is that here's a virus or a
ideja je da je ovde virus ili a
piece of malware that gets into the
malware koji ulazi u
system and if you don't have a book
sistem i ako nemate knjigu
malware until it partners up and
zlonamerni softver dok se ne poveže i
download this other no I think it sounds
preuzmi ovaj drugi ne mislim da zvuči
to me as though it actually goes out and
za mene kao da zapravo izlazi i
gets its partner and and they both wreak
dobija svog partnera i oboje se iskaljuju
havoc then if you if your virus scanner
pustoši onda ako je vaš virus skener
happens to get rid of the one it go the
desi se da se oslobodimo one koju ide
other one of it goes and gets reinfect
drugi ode ide i dobija reinfect
right and it's probably one of those
i to je verovatno jedan od njih
things that morph some changes in
stvari koje se pretvaraju u neke promene
everything so sounds kind of that way
sve tako zvuči na taj način
and this being from Microsoft to I mean
i to od Microsofta do toga
the they're probably testing with
sa kojim verovatno testiraju
security essentials not with ESET so
esencijalne bezbednosti nije sa ESET-om
yeah I mean it's really tough to get it
Da , mislim da je teško dobiti ga
on our own product Voyager 1 may soon be
na našem proizvodu Voyager 1 uskoro može biti
the first man-made object to enter inter
prvi objekat koji je napravio čovek da uđe u inter
teller int I try interstellar again give
Teller int Pokušavam interstellar opet dati
it a go maybe the first man-made object
to je možda prvi objekat koji je napravio čovek
to enter interstellar space really it
da uđemo u međuzvjezdani prostor
could be any day but it could also be
mogao bi biti bilo koji dan, ali bi mogao biti
several more years that's a quote from
još nekoliko godina to je citat iz
dr. ed stone who has worked on the
dr. kamen koji je radio na
Voyager project from the very beginning
Voyager projekt od samog početka
he can't say when the voyager 1
ne može reći kada je putnik 1
spacecraft will leave the solar system
letelica će napustiti Sunčev sistem
but he believes the moment is close the
ali on veruje da je trenutak blizu
latest data from this extraordinary
najnovije podatke iz ovog izvanrednog
progra pardon this week's science
Prošle nedelje nauka
journal suggests it is surfing right on
časopis sugerira da je surfanje pravo na
the very edge of our sons domain the
na samoj ivici domena naših sinova
particle streaming away from our star
čestica koja se udaljila od naše zvezde
have been reduced to a trickle at its
su svedeni na kapljicu
present location 18.5 billion kilometers
sadašnja lokacija 18,5 milijardi kilometara
from Earth particles flying towards it
od čestica Zemlje koje lete ka njoj
from interstellar space by contrast have
iz međuzvezdanog prostora nasuprot tome
jumped markedly in the past year so
naglo skočio u prošloj godini
there's other matter out there there
tamo je druga stvar
that's what it's telling us it all
to nam sve govori
points to an imminent departure which
ukazuje na skori odlazak koji
would make Voyager the first man-made
Voyager bi bio prvi čovek
object to cross into the space between
objekt za prelazak u prostor između
stars launched way back in 1977 the
zvezde su lansirane davne 1977. godine
probe is now traveled so far from home
Sonda je sada putovala tako daleko od kuće
that it's constant chatter of data makes
to je konstantno lupanje podataka
seven takes 17 hours to arrive at the US
sedam traje 17 sati da stignu u SAD
Space Agency's receiving number
Broj prijemne agencije
so that's surprising to me I would have
tako da me to iznenađuje
expected it to be much higher 17 hours
očekivao je da će biti mnogo više 17 sati
but I can't they leave that it's still
ali ne mogu da odu da je još
communicating far away plutonium is a
komuniciranje daleko plutonij je
pretty viable battery source yes but
prilično održiv izvor baterije da, ali
even just the fact that the the signal
čak i samo činjenica da je signal
is making it this far in only 17 hours
Daleko je za 17 sati
what's that 2020 yeah like what what is
šta je to 2020. da kao što je ono što je
interstellar space we don't really know
međuzvezdani prostor koji zapravo ne znamo
is there is it because of the
je to zbog toga
convergence of all this matter and
konvergencija svega ovoga i
energy is it gonna just destroy the
energija Hoće li samo uništiti
thing who knows or could it keep going
stvar koja zna ili može nastaviti
and keep broadcasting because if it only
i nastavite sa emitovanjem jer ako samo
takes 17 hours to get the data to us
potrebno je 17 sati da nam se dostave podaci
yeah that's really cool Wow it could be
da, to je stvarno cool Wow to moglo biti
like a horizon like what's beyond the
kao horizont poput onoga iza
horizon it looks like its infinite right
horizont izgleda kao beskonačno pravo
and then you get there and it's like wow
i onda stignete tamo i to je kao vau
yes it's the truman show and then what's
Da, to je truman, a onda šta
on we're gonna get it on the other side
na to ćemo dobiti na drugoj strani
of this is gonna collide into the wall
Ovo će se sudariti u zid
okay a trio of chinese scientists have
U redu, troje kineskih naučnika ima
discovered a breakthrough process that
to je otkrio proces probijanja
could at least in theory allow a DVD to
barem u teoriji dopustio DVD
store a whopping 1000 terabytes or a
pohranite nevjerojatnih 1000 terabajta ili a
full fatal bite oh now we get to learn
puni fatalni ugriz oh sada ćemo naučiti
the true meaning of terabyte a thousand
pravo značenje terabajta hiljadu
terabytes on an optical disk wow that's
terabajta na optičkom disku wow to je
a you know but I'm never gonna say oh we
a znaš, ali nikad neću reći o nama
never need to store that much data
nikada ne treba da pohranjujete toliko podataka
because i remember when i had my you
jer sam se kad sam imao tebe
know 20 20 meg hard drive and I got my
znam 20 20 meg hard disk i dobio sam svoj
360 Meg hard drive yeah my friends they
360 Meg hard disk Da moji prijatelji oni
never feel that real never in a million
nikad ne osećam da nikada nije ni milion
years fill that on yet here you are that
Godine popunite to, ali evo vas
was megabytes not gigabyte but with a
megabajta nije gigabajt, već sa a
thousand terabytes on a single disk even
hiljadu terabajta na jednom disku
with spirally light optical cables
sa spiralno svetlim optičkim kablovima
that's gonna take a long time you know
to će dugo trajati
imal of 60 gig with my current internet
imal od 60 gig sa mojim trenutnim internetom
and I quite often go over
i često prelazim
Bay has just been completely demolished
Zaljev je upravo potpuno uništen
but yeah yeah the new blu-ray discs are
ali da da, novi Blu-ray diskovi su
1 1 petabyte Wow when you rip it you're
1 1 petabajta Wow kada ga parati si
gonna have to find a new encoding mpeg-4
morati da nađem novi kodirani mpeg-4
just storage capacity the DVD is limited
samo kapacitet skladištenja DVD-a je ograničen
by the size of the laser beam burning
veličinom laserskog snopa
the small pits that represent the
male jame koje predstavljaju
streams of data blu-ray increased its
tokovi podataka blu-ray povećali su
capacity by switching to even smaller
kapaciteta prebacivanjem na još manji
blue lasers but the storage capacity of
plavi laseri, ali kapacitet skladištenja
that technology maxed out as well in
da je tehnologija na maksimumu, kao iu
1873 a German physicist named Ernst a be
1873. nemački fizičar Ernst a be
found that a beam of light focused
otkrili su da je snop svetlosti fokusiran
through a lens could not be any smaller
kroz objektiv ne može biti manji
than half of the lights wavelength and
više od polovine svetlosnih talasa i
for visible light which is used to burn
za vidljivo svetlo koje se koristi za sagorevanje
digital media disk that's around 500
digitalni medijski disk koji je oko 500
nanometers so instead of breaking that
nanometara tako da se to ne razbije
law the researchers found a way to work
istraživači su pronašli način rada
around it by using two beams of light to
oko njega pomoću dve svetlosne zrake
cancel each other out and by ensuring
međusobno se poništite i osiguravajući
the beams don't completely overlap a
grede se ne preklapaju u potpunosti a
much smaller beam can be created to burn
mnogo manji snop može biti stvoren da izgori
even smaller pits on the disk massively
čak i manje jame na disku masovno
increasing its capacity since writing
povećanjem kapaciteta od pisanja
1000 terabytes of data would take
Trebalo bi 1000 terabajta podataka
forever developing faster ways to burn
zauvek razvija brže načine za sagorevanje
discs will be necessary before consumers
diskovi će biti potrebni prije potrošača
are ready to adopt the new technology
spremni su da usvoje novu tehnologiju
but the prospects of DVDs and blu-rays
ali izgledi za DVD i blu-ray
taking a quantum leap in storage
kvantni skok u skladištu
capacity is still incredibly exciting
kapacitet je još uvijek nevjerojatno uzbudljiv
I'll say I just wanted what integrity
Reći ću da sam samo htio integritet
the material in which i'm holding the
materijal u kojem sam držao
pits that'll be because of its porous at
jame koje će biti zbog njegove poroznosti
all you know down to whatever number of
sve što znate, bez obzira na broj
nanometers the the in the Vietnam eaters
nanometara u Vijetnamu
what you think about if there was like
šta mislite o tome da li postoji
this most yes that would be exactly if
ovo najviše da da bi bilo tačno ako
you were to pronounce ok we nanometer
izgovorili ste ok mi nanometar
the way you pronounce kill kilometer it
način na koji izgovaraš ubijanje kilometra
would be known ometer and it sounds like
bio bi poznat ometer i zvuči kao
something for measuring nanometers how
nešto za mjerenje nanometara kako
big is it physically how big is a DVD
veliki je fizički koliko je veliki DVD
like four and a half inches across or so
kao četiri i po inča ili više
somewhere around there around there and
negde tamo negde
you think about like it the most men
ti misliš o tome kao o većini muškaraca
you'd scratch so if in that amount of
tako bi se ogrebao ako u toj količini
space there is a petabyte of data and
prostor ima petabajt podataka i
you get even the slightest little
čak i najmanje
fingerprint for loop just a little bit
otisak prsta za petlje malo
with gigs upon gigs
sa svirkama na svirkama
data from the little peanut realities of
podaci iz male realnosti kikirikija
a clean room you won't be able to know
čistu sobu koju nećete moći znati
it'll have to be an enclosed in itunes
to će morati biti zatvoreno u itunes-u
could we go back to the to the carts
možemo li da se vratimo do kola
where the disc is actually protected
gde je disk zaista zaštićen
inside of a cart like a floppy disk oh
unutar kolica kao disketa oh
thanks well i don't know i'm guessing
hvala dobro ja ne znam da sam nagađanje
how would you do it you have more
kako biste to uradili imate više
there's more last week that means the
prošle nedelje to znači više
availability is not a popular game
dostupnost nije popularna igra
portal on linux and now half-life 2 the
portal na linux i sada polu-život 2 the
first person shooter game also made by
prva osoba pucač igra također napravio
valve has migrated from beta 2 stable
ventil je migrirao iz beta 2 stabilnog
release on steam for Linux showing even
izdanje na paru za Linux koji pokazuje čak
further the valve is serious about
dalje ventil je ozbiljan
expanding its steam gaming platform for
proširuje svoju platformu za parnu igru
linux users half-life 2 episodes one and
linux korisnici polu-život 2 epizoda jedan i
two as well as the spin-off mini game
dva kao i spin-off mini igra
half-life two Lost Coast see their beta
polu-život dva izgubljene obale vide svoju beta verziju
tags shaken off and are now available in
oznake su se otresle i sada su dostupne u
steam for 10 bucks and dice it's getting
para za 10 dolara i kockica dobija
serious folks linux is a gaming platform
ozbiljni ljudi linux je igraća platforma
just saying get the full story as a
samo kažem da dobijem celu priču kao
category 5 TV / newsroom the category 5
kategorija 5 TV / redakcija kategorije 5
TV news room is researched by roy wa ash
Prostoriju za TV vijesti istražuje roy wa ash
and stephen Delaney with contributions
i Stephen Delaney sa doprinosima
by you viewers if you have a new story
vi gledaoci ako imate novu priču
you think is worthy of on-air mention
Mislite da je vredno pominjanja u eteru
email newsroom category five dot TV for
email newsroom kategorija pet dot TV za
the category 5 TV news room I'm Eric
u TV sobi za vijesti kategorije 5 Ja sam Eric
Kidd thanks Eric check out ads are calm
Kidd hvala Eric provjeriti oglase su mirni
for the fastest asynchronous JavaScript
za najbrži asinkroni JavaScript
ad serving code at zerk dot-com my mom
kod za prikazivanje oglasa na zerk dot-com moja mama
my a3 ol mum said what's hazard when I
moja mama je rekla šta je opasnost kada sam
wear the shirt I was last I was your
nosim majicu koju sam zadnji put bio tvoj
everything yeah variant I went over for
sve da varijanta Otišao sam za
a visit okay like after I was like mom
poseta u redu kao što sam bila kao mama
was watching no no no no
nije gledao ne ne ne ne
oh no no she hasn't figured out the
oh ne ne, nije shvatila
computer yet but alright but she must
kompjuteru, ali u redu, ali mora
ask me about five times when I explain
pitaj me pet puta kad ti objasnim
it and then again so what's answer it's
i onda ponovo pa šta je odgovoriti na to
asynchronous JavaScript serving code mom
asinkroni JavaScript kod posluživanja mama
it's the world's fastest asynchronous
to je najbrži asinhroni na svijetu
jazz code that's yes I mean think in
jazz kod koji mislim da mislim
terms of the cloud mom sorry I'm leaving
u smislu oblaka mama mi je žao što odlazim
that alone all right we got a couple
da je sve u redu, imamo par
more questions there that we can sure
ima još pitanja koja smo sigurni
why not thanks for sending in your
zašto ne hvala što ste poslali vašu
question folks live at category 5 TV
Pitajte ljude koji žive u kategoriji 5 TV
don't forget you can give us call I know
ne zaboravi da nas možeš nazvati Znam
you know we're not at all used to taking
znate da nismo navikli na to
calls in studio but 2545 cat5 TV if
pozive u studio ali 2545 cat5 TV ako
you'd like to give us a call let's do it
Želite da nas nazovete
somebody call an occult or terminal arms
neko naziva okultno ili terminalno oružje
up sorry okay oh we're gonna have an
gore žao, ok ćemo imati
email from old salt hey I have an
e-mail od stare soli hej imam
emachine ET 1331 G dash 0 3 w with six
emachine ET 1331 G dash 0 3 w sa šest
gig of ram oh do you want all the so i
svirka ovna o, hoćete li sve tako i
go through all the spectre I'm AMD
proći kroz sve aveti sam AMD
athlon too yeah it's got a big hard
i athlon da, to je jako teško
drive it's got nvidia graphics okay of
drive ima nvidia grafike u redu od
course the ethernet and here's an HP
Naravno, Ethernet i evo HP-a
all-in-one printer so it's a basic
sve-u-jednom štampač tako da je osnovni
consumer computer off the shelf emachine
potrošačko računalo s polica emachine
you want to note we can add ubuntu is
želimo napomenuti da možemo dodati ubuntu je
the third OS without any problems what
treći OS bez ikakvih problema
os's are on there right now well let's
Os su sada tamo i dobro
see we go back to Scott X on 32-bit in
vidimo se vratiti na Scott X na 32-bitnom
windows 7 home premium 64-bit nice so
Windows 7 Home Premium 64-bitni lijepo tako
yeah do it here's what I would do okay
Da, uradi to ovako
what do we do Eric any time we're gonna
šta da radimo Ericu kad god želimo
be repartitioning our hard drive back it
preraspodeli naš hard disk nazad
up back it up back it up back it okay so
gore ga natrag gore natrag gore to u redu tako
get clonezilla clonezilla org run a full
dobiti clonezilla clonezilla org pokrenuti punu
backup of your entire hard drive
sigurnosna kopija cijelog tvrdog diska
including the partition systems because
uključujući i particijske sisteme, jer
you just want to take that risk if you
samo želiš da preuzmeš taj rizik ako ti
are reasonably experienced with
s razumnim iskustvom
partitioning then it's not going to be a
particioniranje onda to neće biti
problem for you're going to be able to
problem ti ćeš biti u stanju da
create a partition install to that
napravite instalaciju particije na to
partition with the installer and a boon
particiju sa instalatorom i blagom
to and Ubuntu is going to install a new
i Ubuntu će instalirati novo
bootloader so you're not going to have
bootloader tako da nećete imati
the windows boot loader anymore it's
Windows boot loader je više
going to be the grub boot loader
će biti grub boot loader
and with grub it's going to then present
i sa grub-om će se onda pojaviti
you when you first boot the computer
kada prvi put pokrenete računar
with windows XP Windows 7 and Ubuntu as
sa Windows XP Windows 7 i Ubuntu as
well as a couple other options like
kao i nekoliko drugih opcija
recovery mode for linux and and possibly
mod oporavka za Linux i eventualno
memtest and things like that but
memtest i takve stvari, ali
regardless it's going to create a triple
bez obzira što će stvoriti trostruku
boot environment for you and give you
boot okruženje za vas i dati vam
the menu to do it reason that we want to
meni se to radi zbog toga želimo da
use clonezilla first is just so that you
koristiti clonezilla prvi je samo tako da vas
have a fallback plan just in case
imati rezervni plan za svaki slučaj
something goes wrong or you know it's
nešto pođe naopako ili znate da je
pretty unlikely but I don't like to take
prilično neverovatno ali ne volim da je uzmem
those risks and it's not going to take
te rizike i to neće biti potrebno
you much time to run a clone clonezilla
Imate mnogo vremena da pokrenete klon clonezilla
will create a backup of not just your
će kreirati rezervnu kopiju ne samo vašeg
data but the whole the whole hard drive
podataka, ali ceo ceo hard disk
including the partition tables if you do
uključujući tabele particija ako to učinite
a device to image style clone what is
uređaj za kloniranje stila koji je
neat about that is that when it creates
o tome je uredno kada se stvara
the image it's not going to store empty
slika neće biti prazna
sectors so if you have the 700 gig hard
sektorima, tako da ako imate 700 giga teško
drive and you're only actually using 200
vozite i zapravo samo koristite 200
gigs of the data of the drives capacity
nastupi podataka o kapacitetima pogona
it will only be a 200 gigabyte image so
to će biti samo slika od 200 gigabajta
it works out quite well for you so give
to dobro funkcionira za vas tako dajte
that a try and and let us know how it
da pokuša i javite nam kako je
goes but yes it will automatically pick
ide, ali da će automatski izabrati
up your other operating systems and
i druge operativne sisteme i
it'll do it all for you so just be you
sve će to učiniti za tebe, samo budi ti
know be cautious as you're going through
znam da budite oprezni dok prolazite
that and the aboon to installer will
to i umesto instalatera
actually prompt you if you go through
zapravo vas pitati ako prođete
with some of the default it will say do
sa nekim od propusta koji će reći
you want to overwrite the operating
želite prebrisati operativni
systems that are on there or do you want
sistemima koji su tamo ili želite
to add to the free space Ubuntu and it
da dodamo slobodnom prostoru Ubuntu i to
will automatically repartition your hard
automatski će preraspodijeliti vaš tvrdi disk
drive and make a triple boot for you but
vozite i napravite trostruku čizmu za vas, ali
again fall back on that clonezilla image
ponovo se vraćamo na tu sliku klonilije
just in case yeah hmm exactly an old
za svaki slučaj, da
salt has been in the computer since das
sol je u kompjuteru još od das
in the wind windows oh yeah thnkx XP is
u vetrobranskim prozorima oh yeh thnkx XP je
the best version they ever came up with
najbolja verzija koju su ikada smislili
them I just thought of dad I suppose
Mislila sam na oca
like if it was like a battle of
kao da je kao bitka
Microsoft products than XP was kind of
Microsoftovi proizvodi od XP-a su bili nekako
the first stable so to speak the the
prva stabilna , da tako kažem
most stable of the the lion with full
najstabilniji od lava s punim
multitasking right I think it was
mislim da je bilo višezadaćno
revolutionary at the time yeah
revolucionarno u to vreme da
so okay how about another one love it
tako dobro kako o još jednom voli
thanks for question okay and here's one
hvala na pitanju u redu i evo jednog
kick kick how do you say that there
šutiraš kako to kažeš
aren't that many syllables I'm just
nisam toliko slogova
saying though that was just sorry yeah
iako mi je to bilo žao
doc and tonight I had raised because on
Doktore i večeras sam podigao zato što sam nastavio
tonight hi Robby and Rachel oh I use
večeras, hvala, Robby i Rachel
keep a sex on for computers three Linux
zadržati seks na računaru tri Linuxa
one Mac cool and want to keep the
jedan Mac cool i želite zadržati
database files in sync they're not on
datoteke baze podataka u sinkronizaciji nisu uključene
the same land but can connect via the
istu zemlju, ali se može povezati preko
internet using SSH I plan to have one
Internet koristeći SSH Planiram da ga imam
machine be the master and have cron run
mašina je glavni i ima cron run
our sink in each direction from each
naš sudoper u svakom smjeru od svakog
machine to the master okay I'll have our
stroj za majstora, u redu, ja ću
sink make a copy before overwriting I
sudopera napravite kopiju pre prepisivanja I
think this will work but it seems a bit
mislim da će ovo funkcionisati, ali izgleda malo
clutchy another technical word ah la g
još jedna tehnička reč ah la g
pledgie pledgie do you have a better way
pledgie pledgie imate li bolji način
to do this I love the show it's always a
da uradim ovo volim emisiju, to je uvek a
lot of fun and very informative I really
Vrlo zabavno i vrlo informativno
enjoyed the back and forth banter I
uživao sam u naprijed i natrag
usually can't watch the whole thing live
obično ne mogu da gledam celu stvar uživo
but we'll watch it later on thanks kick
ali kasnije ćemo ga gledati zahvaljujući kick-u
kick kick girl well kkkkkk kick and we
šutira djevojka dobro kkkkkk kick i mi
will pass along let's see we get high to
proći ćemo, hajde da vidimo da smo visoko
Rachel yes uh I think you're I think
Rachel da, mislim da mislim
you're really on the right track yeah it
ti si stvarno na pravom putu
seems like you understand SSH and the
izgleda kao da razumete SSH i
ability to actually connect to a server
mogućnost da se stvarno povežete sa serverom
using like an ssh connection because
koristeći kao ssh vezu jer
you're doing that with our sink what if
to radite sa našim sudoporom što ako
though we were to take a different
mada smo morali da prihvatimo drugačije
approach and instead of using our sink
prilazimo i umesto da koristimo naš sudoper
to think each computer and potentially
da razmisli o svakom kompjuteru i potencijalno
cause issues and then you've got actual
uzrokujte probleme i onda imate stvarnost
individual copies of this file scattered
pojedinačne kopije ovog fajla raštrkane
on each computer well I guess it depends
na svakom računaru dobro mislim da to zavisi
is are the are you always connected see
jeste da li ste uvek povezani
I want to imagine that you're always
Želim da zamislim da si uvek
online if you're always online i would
online ako ste uvijek online, ja bih
set up the ssh connection that you
postavite ssh vezu koju ste
already have established and on that ssh
već smo uspostavili i na tom ssh
connection would lay for the one file
veza bi ležala za jedan fajl
that gets backed up and that one file
koji se podupire i taj jedan fajl
would be accessible through an FS tab
bio bi dostupan preko FS kartice
entry so that your each of your other
tako da svaki vaš drugi
computers would then
kompjuteri bi onda
have the mount point set up in the same
postavite tačku montiranja u istu
way so that they all share the same file
tako da svi dele isti fajl
through ssh and they're all connecting
kroz ssh i svi se povezuju
to that server and they're all able to
na taj server i svi oni mogu
modify that file and use that file and
modifikujte tu datoteku i koristite tu datoteku i
all that concept but if you ever lose
sav taj koncept, ali ako ikada izgubite
your internet connection then you lose
Vašu internet vezu onda izgubite
access to that file so that's where if
pristup tom fajlu, tako da je to gde
you're on a boon to you can use things
ti si na blagodeti jer možeš koristiti stvari
like Ubuntu one and you don't have to be
kao Ubuntu i ne morate biti
on a boom tube you can just install the
na cijevi cjevovoda možete instalirati
one do one who boat we do like a boot
jedan čini onaj koji se ukrcava kao da čizma
cool definitely but it boom to one is
svakako cool, ali to je jedan bum
like a cloud-based storage place so it
kao skladište bazirano na oblaku
gives you the same thing but what's
daje vam istu stvar, ali ono što je
advantageous about Boone 21 is that if
prednost u vezi sa Boone 21 je da ako
you lose your internet connection your
izgubili ste internet vezu
computer will fall back on to a local
Računar će se vratiti na lokalnu
copy automatically that it is already
automatski kopirajte da je već
synced from the cloud so that might be
sinhronizovano iz oblaka tako da može biti
the route I would take but SSH would be
put koji bih ja uzeo, ali SSH bi bio
the first one I would do we we did a
prvi koji bih uradio mi smo uradili
feature on the show if you go to
u emisiji, ako idete na
category five dot TV I'll just quickly
kategorija pet dot TV Ja ću samo brzo
grab you the episode number i'm going to
Uhvati broj epizode na koju idem
do a quick search for SLL CIFS SMB FS or
brzo potražite SLL CIFS SMB FS ili
m8s mb f s FS tab why don't I do that
m8s mb fs FS tab, zašto to ne radim
I'm going to go with the old SMB FS just
Idem sa starim SMB FS-om
because that will take you right to the
jer to će vas odvesti pravo na
original episode and just be mindful
originalnu epizodu i samo budite svesni
that you'll need to change it to cifs
da ćete morati da ga promenite u cif
because as sm bffs has been deprecated
jer je sm bffs odbačen
i'm on episode number 296 actually we
Ja sam u epizodi broj 296 zapravo mi
talked about that very thing so check
razgovarali o toj stvari tako da proverite
that out and that refers to so episode
to se odnosi na tako epizodu
number 296 talks about it in viewer
broj 296 govori o tome u gledaocu
questions and it refers to our lesson
pitanja i odnosi se na našu lekciju
that happened on episode 266 about 12
to se dogodilo u epizodi 266 oko 12 godina
minutes into the show which shows you
minuta u emisiju koja vam pokazuje
how to set that up so that they're all
kako to podesiti tako da su sve
connected all the time to the server
sve vreme povezani sa serverom
which is really really cool I love that
što je stvarno stvarno cool volim to
I've got just to give it an example
Moram samo da dam primer
scenario god I realized that my wife's
Scenarij bog sam shvatio da je moja žena
documents like the files on her computer
dokumenata kao što su datoteke na njenom kompjuteru
in the documents folder that her backup
u fascikli sa dokumentima da je njena rezerva
hadn't been running because it'd gotten
nije trčao jer je dobio
too large and it was not working so well
prevelika i nije dobro funkcionirala
what am i doing why does she have her
šta ja radim zašto je ima
own independent documents folder I've
sopstvenu fasciklu nezavisnih dokumenata
got a server here so what I did is I
Imam server ovde pa sam ja to uradio
created a document share on the server
kreirao je deljenje dokumenta na serveru
and I used FS tab using this procedure
i koristio sam FS karticu koristeći ovu proceduru
to change her documents into a
da promijeni svoje dokumente u a
point I moved all her files down to the
Tačnije , premjestio sam sve svoje dokumente do
server into the share and then i mounted
server u udeo i onda sam montiran
through FS tab documents so now when she
preko FS tabulatorskih dokumenata tako sada kada je ona
brings up document she's none the wiser
donosi dokument koji nije pametniji
she just still sees all her documents
ona još uvijek vidi sve svoje dokumente
but actually they're on the server it's
ali zapravo su na serveru
still the same place it's still in her
još uvijek na istom mjestu gdje je još uvijek u njoj
home folder and a folder called
home folder i folder
documents because that's the mount point
dokumenata jer je to točka montiranja
and it's all there so then I back up the
i sve je tu pa onda podupirem
server on a nightly basis off-site and
server na noćnoj bazi off-site i
all of her stuff is involved in that
sve njene stvari su uključene u to
background so I love that method of
pozadinu pa volim taj metod
doing things so let us know what you
radite stvari tako da nam javite šta vi
choose and and otherwise I think you're
izabrati i inače mislim da ste vi
on a really good track with our sink but
na stvarno dobrom putu sa našim sudoperu ali
just you need to figure out some kind of
samo trebate smisliti neku vrstu
a script to make sure that it doesn't
skriptu da bi se uverio da to nije
overwrite it if they're having like if
prepisati ga ako im se sviđa ako
the changes if the changes were done
promene su izvršene
with my computer I don't want to get
sa mojim kompjuterom ne želim da dobijem
that file overwritten another computer
ta datoteka prepisuje drugi računar
right it can get a little bit
desno može dobiti malo
complicated that's where an already
komplicirano je to gdje je već
existing cloud infrastructure like
postojeća infrastruktura oblaka
Ubuntu one would be advantageous all
Ubuntu bi svima bio koristan
right another question I think we'll
pravo drugo pitanje mislim da ćemo
squeeze it in okay here's a quick one
Stisni ga u redu, evo ga brzo
from I guess this is mikey mikey mighty
Mislim da je ovo Mikey Mikey moćan
Scotty gloopy alright so I'm going to be
Scotty gloopy u redu, tako da ću biti
playing music in a bustling city park
svira muziku u užurbanom gradskom parku
and I was wondering if we could if I
i pitao sam se da li možemo
could use to DSLRs to do a multicam live
mogla koristiti za DSLR da uradim multicam uživo
stream could we do it using a macbook
stream bi to mogli napraviti pomoću Macbook-a
pro I know in your video you have
Pro znam u vašem videu
separate pci cards for each camera now
odvojene PCI kartice za svaku kameru
the DSLR is gonna if you're hoping in to
DSLR će biti ako se nadate
hdmi it's our HD hdmi output in which
hdmi je naš HD hdmi izlaz u kojem
case your macbook pro doesn't have an
slučaju vaš MacBook Pro nema
input for hdmi it has an output for hdmi
ulaz za hdmi ima izlaz za hdmi
but you keep it like that hdmi cable
ali zadržite ga kao taj hdmi kabl
from your camera into the hdmi output on
sa kamere na hdmi izlaz
your laptop and you've got two signals
Vaš laptop i imate dva signala
clashing with each other and could cause
sukobljavaju se i mogu izazvati
some damage so you're going to still
neke štete, tako da ćete i dalje
need some kind of capture device if your
trebate neku vrstu uređaja za snimanje ako vaš
MacBooks are and if your macbook is new
MacBook-ovi su i ako je vaš Macbook novi
enough then you might be able to add
dovoljno onda možete dodati
like an external thunderbolt or USB 3
kao vanjski grom ili USB 3
capture device like a black magic
snimite uređaj kao crnu magiju
intensity external unit that would work
intenzitet vanjske jedinice koja bi radila
and then you use something like wire
i onda koristite nešto poput žice
cast from cap
cast from cap
five dot TV / Wirecast to do the
pet dot TV / Wirecast
switching as you saw on the show the
kao što ste videli na emisiji
DSLRs are going to probably shut off on
DSLR-ovi će se vjerojatno isključiti
you after a little while so if you're
posle malo, pa ako ste vi
doing like a flash mob or something
radi kao flash mob ili nešto slično
where it's going to be done in five
gde će biti u pet
minutes flat then you do just fine and
minuta stan onda si to sasvim dobro i
you get some amazing video live though
ipak dobijate neverovatan video uživo
what I would do give that to the
ono što bih ja dao tom
scenario is i would set up my DSLRs and
Scenario je da bih postavio svoje DSLR-ove i
i would use those to shoot the video
Koristio bih ih za snimanje videa
recorded to its internal storage or two
zabilježen u njegovoj internoj memoriji ili dvije
it's flat flash drive or whatever shoot
to je ravan flash disk ili bilo koji snimak
it enfold like full HD and then you're
ona se savija kao full HD i onda ste
getting that away from the streaming out
oduzimamo to od strujanja
of it and then just have a handycam or
od toga, a onda samo da kupite Handycam ili
some other kind of thing like we use you
Neku drugu vrstu stvari kao što smo mi
just a DV camera with a firewalker your
samo DV kameru sa firewalker-om
macbook is going to have a firewire
macbook će imati firewire
input so then it's only SD quality it's
tako da je to samo SD kvaliteta
really low quality but at least then
zaista niske kvalitete, ali barem tada
have you've got to HD DSLRs recording
imate snimanje HD DSLR-ova
full quality full frame rate 60 seconds
puna kvaliteta cijelog kadra 60 sekundi
of frames a second it's fantastic video
kadrova u sekundi je fantastičan video
and then you've got the one that's
i onda imate onu koja je
shooting live and it's stream it's just
pucanje uživo i to je tok
streaming really crummy quality video
Stvarni video snimci su veoma lošeg kvaliteta
but it's it's good for four straight so
ali to je dobro za četiri ravno tako
then you take your high-definition
onda uzmete svoju visoku definiciju
camera sources you take those ones back
izvore iz fotoaparata vraćate nazad
to the studio you pose produce them and
u studio koji postavljate, i to
you make them into a nice video and
napravite ih u lep video i
everything looks really really good when
sve izgleda stvarno jako dobro
people actually download the thing off
ljudi su zapravo skinuli stvar
of or watch it on youtube or whatever it
ili gledati na youtube-u ili kako god
is so that would be the way that I would
da bi to bio način na koji bih ja to uradio
approach all right what's that somebody
prilazi dobro šta je to neko
saying your mic so can you guys hear me
govoreći svoj mikrofon tako da me možete čuti
through all that the mics are loose that
kroz sve to mici su izgubili to
mics aren't the boss I didn't check your
mics nisu šef, nisam provjerio vaš
visible Museum a good why might I didn't
vidljiv muzej dobro zašto možda nisam
check this oh noes olive you're good all
provjerite da li je sve dobro
right you know what did you guys hear
da li znate šta ste čuli
what I said because I don't mind
ono što sam rekao jer mi ne smeta
repeating myself if I need to
ponavljam se ako treba
just for that one question oh sorry most
samo za to jedno pitanje
of the time you cut out and there's a
onog vremena kada ste ga isekli i tamo je
lot of static well if you can hear me we
puno statičnog, ako me čujete
should say hello to our viewers on
treba da pozdravimo naše gledaoce
YouTube blip TV Miro internet TV first
YouTube blip TV Miro internet TV prvi
run TV Roku etc okay we're gonna
run TV Roku itd redu ćemo
actually redo the whole show right now
zapravo, preraditi ceo show sada
so well no jot you are so kidding right
tako dobro, nemojte se šaliti
I'm watching the chat room here Oh jots
Gledam sobu za ćaskanje
pulling our leg I don't know well no
povlačenjem naših nogu ne dobro ne poznaju
Eric's mike is fun you guys know how to
Ericov mikrofon je zabava koju vi znate
private message right no way Oh guys we
privatna poruka right no way Oh guys we
love you show's over get out of here
Ljubav koju pokazuješ je gotova odavde
thanks for joining us tonight next week
hvala što si nam se pridružio večeras sledeće nedelje
is gonna be really exciting crystal
biće stvarno uzbudljiv kristal
Wells is gonna be here with me in studio
Wells će biti ovde sa mnom u studiju
and she's way better looking in more
i bolje je izgledati više
charming than I that aside we've got
šarmantan nego što to imam na stranu
this device to give away this is the
ovaj uređaj da oda ovo je
seven port USB 2.0 hub got that to give
sedam port USB 2.0 hub je dobio to dati
away and we're gonna be showing you how
daleko i mi ćemo vam pokazati kako
to convert our photos into video
pretvoriti naše fotografije u video
slideshows using free software so don't
slideshows koristeći slobodan softver tako da ne
miss that next Tuesday night so have a
promašite da sledeći utorak uveče imate i
fantastic week everybody and we will see
fantastična nedelja svi ćemo videti
you in a week save it bye bye
za nedelju dana ga spasite zbogom
you
vas
we hope you enjoyed the show category 5
nadamo se da ste uživali u show kategoriji 5
TV broadcasts live from Barrie Ontario
TV emisije uživo iz Barrie Ontario
Canada every tuesday at seven p.m.
Kanada svakog utorka u sedam sati
eastern if you're watching this on
istočni ako gledate ovo
demand or through cable TV check out the
potražite ili putem kablovske TV pogledajte
local show times in your area at
lokalno vrijeme prikazivanja u vašem području
category 5 TV and find out when you can
kategorija 5 TV i saznajte kada možete
watch live and interact in the community
gledajte uživo i komunicirajte u zajednici
chat room category 5 is a production of
Chat room kategorija 5 je proizvodnja
prodigy digital solutions and is
prodigy digital solutions i
licensed under creative commons
licencirani pod Creative Commons
attribution 2.5 canada we'll see you
atribucija 2.5 canada vidjet ćemo vas
next time thanks for tuning in
sledeći put hvala za podešavanje